Guide to the Dale R. Corson papers, 1963-1977
Corson, Dale R. papers, 1963-1977
- Series III. Speeches 1959-1990
  - Talk - Board of Trustees., 15 March 1974 (Box 133, Folder 66)
  - Article - "The Arithmetic of Tenure.", 22 March 1974 (Box 133, Folder 67)
  - Talk - University Senate., 2 April 1974 (Box 133, Folder 68)
  - Speech - Dinner Honoring John N. and Spencer T. Olin., 1 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 69)
  - Remarks - Thomas w. Mackesey Retirement Reception., 4 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 70)
  - Talk - Alpha Delta Phi Reception., 7 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 71)
  - Remarks - "The Shape of Things to Come" at Reunion Forum., 15 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 72)
  - Remarks - Charles Treman Testimonial Dinner., 15 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 73)
  - Talk - University Faculty Meeting., 15 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 74)
  - Notes - Kenneth L. Turk Testimonial Dinner., 16 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 75)
  - Talk - Tower Club Dinner., 23 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 76)
  - Speech - Convocation Address, Cornell Law School., 25 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 77)
  - Remarks - Dinner for Retiring Deans., 28 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 78)
  - Speech - Cornell University Medical College Commencement Address., 29 May 1974 (Box 133, Folder 79)
  - Speech - Olin Chemistry Laboratory Dedication, "Cornell's New strength in Chemistry Research.", 2 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 80)
  - Remarks - Olin Chemistry Laboratory Dedication Dinner., 2 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 81)
  - Speech - Commencement Address., 3 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 82)
  - Speech - ROTC Commissioning., 3 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 83)
  - Remarks - George C. Poppensiek Testimonial Dinner., 7 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 84)
  - Remarks - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1924., 14 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 85)
  - Report to Alumni, Annual Alumni Meeting., 15 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 86)
  - Remarks - Cornell Association of Class Officers., 16 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 87)
  - Remarks - Morris Bishop Memorial Plaque Dedication., 16 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 88)
  - Remarks - Veterinary Research Tower Dedication., 27 June 1974 (Box 133, Folder 89)
  - Remarks - Lasdon House Residence Dedication., 31 July 1974 (Box 133, Folder 90)
  - Remarks - Parents' Convocation., 28 August 1974 (Box 133, Folder 91)
  - Remarks - Students' Convocation., 29 August 1974 (Box 133, Folder 92)
  - Notes - Address to University Senate., 10 Sept. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 93)
  - Remarks - Robert A. Plane Inauguration., 21 Sept. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 94)
  - Article - "Graduate Education in New York State.", 27 Sept. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 95)
  - Speech - "State of the University" at Trustee/Council Weekend., 11 Oct. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 96)
  - Talk - Entomology Centennial Symposium., 14 Oct. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 97)
  - Speech - University Faculty., 16 Oct. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 98)
  - Notes - Introduction of Dr. Ivar Giaver at First Sack Memorial., 16 Oct. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 99)
  - Speech - Tower Club Dinner, Racine, Wisconsin., 31 Oct. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 100)
  - Talk - Committee for Corporate Support., 31 Oct. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 101)
  - Notes - Financial Situation, Middle Management / Press Conference., 8 Nov. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 102)
  - Talk - Dedication of Arecibo Telescope., 19 Nov. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 103)
  - Talk - University Faculty., 25 Nov. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 104)
  - Statement before Pell Committee, Washington., 26 Nov. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 105)
  - Remarks - Howard W. Robison Testimonial Dinner., 5 Dec. 1974 (Box 133, Folder 106)
  - Speech - New York State Agricultural Society., 8 Jan. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 107)
  - Memorandum - "The Deteriorating Financial Scene.", 15 Jan. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 108)
  - Remarks - Acceptance of Honorary Degree, University of Rochester., 1 Feb. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 109)
  - Speech - University of Rochester Trustees., 1 Feb. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 110)
  - Talk - University Faculty., 12 Feb. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 111)
  - Article - "Further Thoughts on Prudent Unrestricted Investment Income Distribution.", 4 March 1975 (Box 133, Folder 112)
  - Notes - "State of the University" for the Board of Trustees., 14 March 1975 (Box 133, Folder 113)
  - Paper - "Thoughts on Long-Term Budget Equilibrium.", 20 March 1975 (Box 133, Folder 114)
  - Speech - Sixth University Senate., 1 April 1975 (Box 133, Folder 115)
  - Remarks - "Where Have the Good Times Gone?", 2 April 1975 (Box 133, Folder 116)
  - Memorandum - Statutory College Budgets, 1975-76, Board of Trustees., 24 April 1975 (Box 133, Folder 117)
  - Summary - 1975-76 New York State Budget., 29 April 1975 (Box 133, Folder 118)
  - Remarks - "Higher Education in New York State" - Cornell Council., 2 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 119)
  - Remarks - "Northeast Rails in Crisis" Symposium., 2 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 120)
  - Talk - University Faculty., 7 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 121)
  - Speech - Phi Kappa Phi., 9 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 122)
  - Talk - Tower Club Dinner., 14 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 123)
  - Speech - Convocation Address, Cornell Law School., 24 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 124)
  - Speech - Commencement Address, Cornell University Medical College., 28 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 125)
  - Remarks - Frank Columbus Memorial Plaque., 31 May 1975 (Box 133, Folder 126)
  - Notes - "State of the University.", 1 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 127)
  - Speech - Commencement Address., 2 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 128)
  - Speech - ROTC Commissioning Ceremony., 2 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 129)
  - Speech - "The Length and Breadth of Education and Learning" -Commencement Address, Kingsborough Community College of the City University of New York., 10 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 130)
  - Remarks - Million Dollar Class Ceremony, Class of 1928, Class of 1950., 13 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 131)
  - Remarks - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1935., 13 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 132)
  - Alumni Report - Annual Alumni Meeting., 14 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 133)
  - Remarks - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1925., 14 June 1975 (Box 133, Folder 134)
  - Remarks - Welcome at the Convocation for New Students., 27 August 1975 (Box 133, Folder 135)
  - Statement - Annual Regents' Legislative Conference, (on Behalf of) Cornell University., 10 Sept. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 136)
  - Statement - Annual Regents' Legislative Conference, (on behalf of) the Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York., 10 Sept. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 137)
  - Speech - Faculty Council of Representatives, University Senate., 24 Sept. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 138)
  - Talk - German- American Seminar, Baltimore., 30 Sept. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 139)
  - Talk - Cornell Council Twenty-Fifth Anniversary., 10 Oct. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 140)
  - Speech - Trustee/Council Weekend., 11 Oct. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 141)
  - Speech - Welcoming Remarks, SUNY Faculty Senate., 24 Oct. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 142)
  - Notes - Hans Bethe Retirement., 24 Oct. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 143)
  - Statement Before the Pell Committee., 28 Oct. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 144)
  - Statement - Campus Safety and Security, and Minority Education., 14 Nov. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 145)
  - Remarks - Ellis H. Robison Testimonial Dinner., 24 NOV. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 146)
  - Remarks - Morton Adams Testimonial Dinner., 3 Dec. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 147)
  - Remarks - Frederick Marcham Testimonial Dinner., 8 Dec. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 148)
  - Introduction - "Cornell in the Seventies.", 11 Jan 1976 (Box 133, Folder 149)
  - Remarks - Frank B. Ingersoll Testimonial Dinner., 16 Jan. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 150)
  - Speech - "State of the University" Board of Trustees., 30 Jan. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 151)
  - Speech - Statement on Athletics, Board of Trustees., 30 Jan. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 152)
  - Speech - Statement on Self -Government, Board of Trustees., 30 Jan. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 153)
  - Editorial - "Higher Education: Harshness and Hope.", Feb. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 154)
  - Speech - "The Future of the Private University" - American Physical Society., 2 Feb. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 155)
  - Manuscript Excerpts - American Physical Society., 2 Feb. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 156)
  - Comments re Cornell for "National Geographic.", 6 Feb. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 157)
  - Letters and Papers to Professor Dannhauser., 1 March 1976 (Box 133, Folder 158)
  - Talk - Board of Trustees., 19 March 1976 (Box 133, Folder 159)
  - Remarks - Cornell Bicentennial Convocation., 10 April 1976 (Box 133, Folder 160)
  - Talk - Faculty Council of Representatives., 28 April 1976 (Box 133, Folder 161)
  - Talk - Tower Club Dinner., 29 April 1976 (Box 133, Folder 162)
  - News Release - Statement on Minority Education., 20 May 1976 (Box 133, Folder 163)
  - Remarks - Convocation Address, Cornell Lav School., 22 May 1976 (Box 133, Folder 164)
  - Remarks - Commencement Address, Cornell University Medical College., 26 May 1976 (Box 133, Folder 165)
  - Speech - ROTC Commissioning., 28 May 1976 (Box 133, Folder 166)
  - Speech - Commencement Address., 28 May 1976 (Box 133, Folder 167)
  - Remarks - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1916., 11 June 1976 (Box 133, Folder 168)
  - Talk - Million Dollar Class Ceremony., 11 June 1976 (Box 133, Folder 169)
  - Notes - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1926., 12 June 1976 (Box 133, Folder 170)
  - Report to Alumni, Annual Alumni Meeting., 12 June 1976 (Box 133, Folder 171)
  - Greetings to the 4-H Club Congress., 29 June 1976 (Box 133, Folder 172)
  - Welcome, Student/Parent Convocation., 31 August 1976 (Box 133, Folder 173)
  - Speech - University Senate., 12 Oct. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 174)
  - Talk - Deans and Vice Presidents Meeting., 12 Oct. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 175)
  - Speech - Trustee/Council Weekend., 22 Oct. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 176)
  - Talk - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges., 16 Nov. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 177)
  - Remarks - J. Robert Buchanan Retirement Dinner., 7 Dec. 1976 (Box 133, Folder 178)
  - Speech - University Faculty., 15 Dec. 1975 (Box 133, Folder 179)
  - Greetings to the New York State 4-H Congress Program., 1977 (Box 133, Folder 180)
  - Speech - Cornell Association of Class Officers Annual Meeting., 29 Jan. 1977 (Box 133, Folder 181)
  - Talk - North Carolina Agricultural and Technical State University., 4 Feb. 1977 (Box 133, Folder 182)
  - Talk - Cornell Campaign Kickoff, Palm Beach Florida., 21 Feb. 1977 (Box 133, Folder 183)
  - Talk - Cornell Campaign Kickoff, Los Angeles., 24 March 1977 (Box 133, Folder 184)
  - Introduction - Olin Library Bookmark Series., April 1977 (Box 133, Folder 185)
  - Paper/Manuscript - "Where Are We and Where Are We Going?" The Circle., 18 April 1977 (Box 133, Folder 186)
  - Talk - New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Faculty Meeting., 4 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 187)
  - Closing Address - Centennial Convocation., 5 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 188)
  - Talk - Tower Club Dinner., 10 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 189)
  - Talk - Engineering Advisory Council., 13 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 190)
  - Talk - Cornell Campaign Leadership Meeting., 16 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 191)
  - Talk - Cornell Women's Club, New York City., 17 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 192)
  - Remarks - Convocation Address, Cornell Law School., 21 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 193)
  - Remarks - Commencement Address, Cornell university Medical College., 25 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 194)
  - Speech - Corson Testimonial., 25 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 195)
  - Speech - Commencement Address., 30 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 196)
  - Speech - ROTC Commissioning., 30 May 1977 (Box 133, Folder 197)
  - Commencement Address - Elmira College., 5 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 198)
  - Remarks - Planetary Nebulae Symposium., 6 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 199)
  - Remarks - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1922., 10 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 200)
  - Remarks - Million Dollar Class Ceremony., 10 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 201)
  - Remarks - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1927., 11 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 202)
  - Remarks - Annual Alumni Meeting, Report to Alumni., 11 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 203)
  - Talk - Unitarian Association., 21 June 1977 (Box 133, Folder 204)
  - Remarks - Acceptance Speech, Association of Colleges and Universities of the State of New York., 28 Sept. 1977 (Box 133, Folder 205)
  - Remarks - Leslie R. Severinghaus Testimonial., 16 Feb. 1978 (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Report to Board of Trustees., March 1978 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Remarks - Arthur Brodeur Speech Written by DRC, Farewell Dinner., 3 March 1978 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - Letters to Chancellors, Status of Cornell University., 9 March 1978 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Remarks - Diedrich K. Willers Memorial Service., 29 March 1978 (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Talk - Deep Springs College., 9 April 1978 (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - Remarks - Mr. and Mrs. Robert Purcell Retirement Dinner., 28 May 1978 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - Manuscript - "Inflation and the Retired Professor" - American Association of University Professors., 7 July 1978 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - Paper - "Washington is the Sunrise Country - Or Is It?", August 1978 (Box 134, Folder 9)
  - Remarks - Inauguration of Edmund T. Cranch, Worcester Polytechnic Institute., 20 Oct. 1978 (Box 134, Folder 10)
  - Remarks - Hazel Purcell Memorial Service, Cape Vincent, NY., 9 Dec. 1978 (Box 134, Folder 11)
  - Paper - "The Wire Ran Out.", 1979 (Box 134, Folder 12)
  - Talk - Saturday Night Club., 27 Jan. 1979 (Box 134, Folder 13)
  - Notes - Franklin A. Long Retirement Dinner., 19 May 1979 (Box 134, Folder 14)
  - Notes - Introduction of President Rhodes, Fiftieth Alumni Reunion., 8 June 1979 (Box 134, Folder 15)
  - Notes - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1919., 9 June 1979 (Box 134, Folder 16)
  - Paper - "The Sun Rises in Maine.", 12 June 1980 (Box 134, Folder 17)
  - Talk - "Extinctions" - Circle Club., 21 Jan. 1981 (Box 134, Folder 18)
  - Remarks - James H. Smith Memorial, Trumansburg NY., 12 June 1981 (Box 134, Folder 19)
  - Talk - Alumni Reunion, Class of 1921., 13 June 1981 (Box 134, Folder 20)
  - Notes - "What Is SPS?" - Physics Colloquium., 15 March 1982 (Box 134, Folder 21)
  - Remarks - Dale R. Corson Hall Building Dedication., 9 Sept. 1982 (Box 134, Folder 22)
  - Remarks by Stuart M. Brown, Corson Dinner., 9 Sept. 1982 (Box 134, Folder 23)
  - Talk - Peace Studies Seminar., 26 Jan. 1983 (Box 134, Folder 24)
  - Talk - Research Club., 9 Feb. 1983 (Box 134, Folder 25)
  - Remarks - Paul Hartman Birthday Celebration., 20 May 1983 (Box 134, Folder 26)
  - Remarks - Eleanor Lambertsen Retirement Symposium., 23 June 1983 (Box 134, Folder 27)
  - Talk - "Censorship, Secrecy, and National Security" - Saturday Night Club., 17 Feb. 1984 (Box 134, Folder 28)
  - Comment - "Revitalizing the Scientific Enterprise" - Syracuse Post Standard., 3 July 1984 (Box 134, Folder 29)
  - Article - "Six Days in Spring" -Carpenter Hall Occupation., 10 July 1984 (Box 134, Folder 30)
  - Speech - "The War Years" - DuBridge Symposium, Rochester NY., 21 Sept. 1984 (Box 134, Folder 31)
  - Paper - "Physics in Sample Universities.", 1985 (Box 134, Folder 32)
  - Speech - "Scientific Communication and National Security" - AAAS Seminar., 30 Jan. 1985 (Box 134, Folder 33)
  - Talk - "China" - Saturday Night Club., 16 Feb. 1985 (Box 134, Folder 34)
  - Speech - "Secrecy, Censorship, and National Security" at the Student Pugwash Meeting., 22 March 1985 (Box 134, Folder 35)
  - Speech - "How Do We Keep Physics a Vital Discipline?" - AAPT-APS., 17 May 1985 (Box 134, Folder 36)
  - Speech - Commencement Address, Wilkes College, Wilkes-Barre, Pennsylvania., 19 May 1985 (Box 134, Folder 37)
  - Introduction to Henry Guerlac's "History of Radar.", 21 Sept. 1985 (Box 134, Folder 38)
  - Paper - "Major Technical Problems Revisited.", 28 Sept. 1985 (Box 134, Folder 39)
  - Remarks - Trevor Cuykendall Memorial., 11 Oct. 1985 (Box 134, Folder 40)
  - Talk - Engineering Council., 5 April 1986 (Box 134, Folder 41)
  - Talk - K-Mart Annual Dinner., May 27, 1986 (Box 134, Folder 42)
  - Talk - Sigma Xi Symposium., October 9, 1986 (Box 134, Folder 43)
  - Remarks - Byron W. Saunders Memorial., January 31, 1987 (Box 134, Folder 44)
  - Background Material - Dale R. Corson, NAE Bueche Award., April 5, 1987 (Box 134, Folder 45)
  - Talk - Saturday Night Club., May 2, 1987 (Box 134, Folder 46)
  - Paper - "Where Has Science Been and Where is it Going?", May 18, 1987 (Box 134, Folder 47)
  - Paper - "The United States Has No Adequate Mechanism to Set National Research Policy.", August 1987 (Box 134, Folder 48)
  - Report - Rutgers Promotion, External Review., August 1987 (Box 134, Folder 49)
  - Paper - "Whither the Research University?", February 15, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 50)
  - Notes - Chinese Universities., March 8, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 51)
  - Talk - RPI Key Executive Seminar., June 9, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 52)
  - Talk - Class of 1933 Reunion., June 11, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 53)
  - Speech - Bueche Award, Washington DC., September 29, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 54)
  - Talk - "Predictions from Stars" at the Saturday Night Club., October 1, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 55)
  - Talk - Cornell Council., October 15, 1988 (Box 134, Folder 56)
  - Talk - McConkey English Seminar., March 14, 1989 (Box 134, Folder 57)
  - Speech - Commencement, University of California Berkeley Commencement., May 26, 1989 (Box 134, Folder 58)
  - Talk - Cornell Adult University., July 5, 1989 (Box 134, Folder 59)
  - Talk - Special Faculty Meeting., December 4, 1964 (Box 134, Folder 60)
  - Paper - "The Sun Rises in Maine" Revisions., May 1981 (Box 134, Folder 61)
  - Paper - "Whither the Research University?", December 5, 1987 (Box 134, Folder 62)
  - Article - "The Willard Straight Takeover" Twentieth Anniversary., April 19, 1989 (Box 134, Folder 63)
  - Remarks - E. Hugh Luckey Memorial Service., October 10, 1989 (Box 134, Folder 64)
  - Notes - United States-Japan Scientific Cooperation., 24 Oct. 1989 (Box 134, Folder 65)
  - Notes - James Krumhansl Retirement Symposium., April 21, 1990 (Box 134, Folder 66)
  - Remarks - Phillips Lounge Dedication., October 17, 1981 (Box 134, Folder 67)
  - Letter to Robert D. Miller re Moynihan and the Senior Chair., October 30, 1989 (Box 134, Folder 68)
  - DRC Biographical Data., 1977-1978 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Drafts and Notes - DRC Speeches., 1971-76 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - DRC Notes for Trustee Discussion., 1974 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - DRC Press Statements., 1970-77 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Notes from Deans* Meetings., 1976-77 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - DRC Annual Report., 1976-77 (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - DRC Final Interview with the Cornell Daily Sun., 1977 (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - DRC Grand Annual Report., 1978 (Box 135, Folder 8)
  - Report of the Commission on Physicians of the Future., 1976 (Box 135, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Ford Foundation, 1959-1973
  - Ford Foundation - Latin America., 1968 (Box 136, Folder 1-2)
  - Ford Foundation - Computers and Communications .DRC notes., 1968 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Ford Foundation - Hungary.DRC notes., 1967 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation - Travel, etc., 1965-1973 (Box 136, Folder 5-6)
  - Ford Foundation - Laboratory Study., 1961-1969 (Box 136, Folder 7-9)
  - Ford Foundation - South America., 1964-1966 (Box 136, Folder 10-15)
  - Ford Foundation - Publications., 1968 (Box 136, Folder 16-18)
  - Ford Foundation - Personal., 1959-69 (Box 136, Folder 19)
  - Ford Foundation - Peru., 1967 (Box 136, Folder 20-21)
  - Ford Foundation - Peru, Argentina, Colombia., 1966-1967 (Box 136, Folder 23-25)
  - Ford Foundation - Universidad del Valle.DRC notes, folder 36., 1963-1968 (Box 136, Folder 26-38)
  - Ford Foundation - Universidad del Valle., 1968 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - Ford Foundation - Peru. DRC notebooks, folder 6., 1967-1973 (Box 137, Folder 2-10)
  - Ford Foundation - Colombia., 1966-1968 (Box 137, Folder 11-19)
  - Ford Foundation - Universidad de los Andes., 1968 (Box 137, Folder 20)
  - Ford Foundation - Argentina., 1962-68 (Box 137, Folder 21-25)
  - Ford Foundation - Latin American Conference., 1965 (Box 137, Folder 26-28)
  - Ford Foundation - Latin American Conference., 1968 (Box 137, Folder 29-31)
  - Ford Foundation - Hungary., 1964-1967 (Box 137, Folder 32-34)
  - Ford Foundation - Poland., 1964-65 (Box 137, Folder 35)
  - John Ongwenyi., 1973 (Box 137, Folder 36)
- Series V. Employment File, 1968-1980
  - DRC Employment Contracts., 1968-1975 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - DRC Employment Contracts., 1968-1980 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Projected College Budgets, 1976-1980, 1975 (Box 141, Folder 1-3)
  - Memos responding to MacNeil Report, 1975 (Box 141, Folder 4-5)
- Tape Recordings, 1973-1977
  - "The Condition of the University" by DRC., October 11, 1973; tr 173
  - Address by DRC to the Student Rally at campus Store., April 8, 1970; tr 187
  - "The Future of the Universit by" DRC., December 1, 1970; tr 202
  - DRC Speech at Tower Club., May 10, 1977; tr 1459
  - DRC With New York Alumni., May 17, 1977; tr 1460-61
  - DRC at Faculty Council of Representatives Meeting. DRC at Cornell Law School Convocation., May 18-21, 1977; tr 1462
  - DRC at Dinner Honoring the Corsons., May 25, 1977; tr 1463-64
  - DRC at Cornell University Medical college Commencement., May 25, 1977; tr 1465
  - DRC at Cornell ROTC Commissioning., May 30, 1977; tr 1465
  - DRC at Class of 1922 Dinner., June 10, 1977; tr 1466
  - DRC at Class of 1927 Dinner., June 11, 1977; tr 1466
  - DRC at Cornell Alumni Annual Meeting., June 11,1977; tr 1467
  - DRC at Cornell University's 109th Commencement, May 30, 1977; tr 1468-69
- Additional Material
  - Confrontation at Cornell report (Box 142)
    A contemporary report by Computer Science professor Peter Wegner on the student protests of the spring of 1969 and the issues faced by Cornell and other universities at that time.